Guide to the Annie Dillard Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Annie Dillard papers
1955-2012
YCAL MSS 422
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
50.85
(78 boxes)
The Annie Dillard Papers document the work and life of writer Annie Dillard. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, notebooks and diaries, teaching materials, drawings, photographs, printed materials, audiovisual materials, computer disks, personal effects, and personal papers. The bulk of the collection consists of Dillard's writings and correspondence.
Dillard, Annie
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Annie Dillard, 1986, 1987, and 1989. Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2000; on the Elizabeth Wakeman Dwight Memorial Fund, 2004 and 2011. Purchased from Annie Dillard on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 52-53 are restricted.
Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted pending reformatting. Access copies of select sound recordings for reference use are noted and available in the main files. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for additional information.
Original computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files disks #1 (Uncat MSS 44) and #1-3 (Uncat ZA MS 90) are available through Access Services. System requirements include CD/DVD drive and file viewing software.
Annie Dillard, 1945-
Annie Dillard was born Meta Ann Doak on April 30, 1945 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. She attended Hollins College near Roanoke, Virginia, and studied creative writing and religion. In her sophomore year, she married her creative writing professor, Richard Dillard, who had a strong influence on her writing. Dillard finished her undergraduate degree in English literature and completed a Masters in Fine Arts from Hollins, in 1968.
After graduate school, Dillard spent her time writing poetry and short stories, some of which she published, and painting and drawing. Interested in the region around her suburban home, filled with forests, mountains, creek, and animals, she wrote about her experiences and observations of area in journals that would become her first book, Pilgrim at Tinker Creek. Published in 1974, the book won Dillard the Pulitzer Prize in 1975 at the age of 29. Dillard divorced her first husband and she moved to Washington state for the position of writer in residence at Western Washington University. She married professor Gary Clevidence and had a daughter. Dillard published Holy the Firm, the memoir An American Chilhood, and two novels, The Living and The Maytrees. She was a professor in the department of English at Wesleyan University in Middletown, CT and now lives in Hillsborough, North Carolina and Wythe County, Virginia with her third husband, professor and writer Robert Richardson.
Scope and Contents
The Annie Dillard Papers document the work and life of writer Annie Dillard. The papers consist of personal and professional correspondence, drafts of writings, notebooks and diaries, teaching materials, drawings, photographs, printed materials, audiovisual materials, computer disks, personal effects, and personal papers, spanning the years 1955-2000. The bulk of the collection consists of Dillard's writings drafts and correspondence. Writings shed light on her creative process and include handwritten and typescript drafts and printed versions of writings, including her books An American Childhood, The Living and Pilgrim at Tinker Creek. Correspondence includes letters from friends, colleagues and readers regarding her writings, both in the publishing process and after publication.
Arrangement
Organized into eight groupings: I. April 1986 Acquisition, 1965-1984. II. August 1987 Acquisition, undated. III. February 1989 Acquisition, 1983-1987. IV. May 2000 Acquisition, 1955-2000. V. May 2000 Acquisition, 1999-2000. VI. August 2004 Acquisition, 1991-1992. VII. January 2011 Acquisition, 1960s-2010. VIII. May 2013 Acquisition, 1987-2012.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital; Audiovisual materials; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographic prints; Sound recordings; Authors; Dillard, Annie
- April 1986 Acquisition, 1965-1984; 1; 15 boxes
  General note
  Formerly classified as Uncat ZA MSS 14.
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975; 11 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Regarding portions of Pilgrim at Tinker Creek published in Sojourners, Connell, Atlantic Monthly, Poetry Review, Prose, and Harper's. Includes correspondence with Buckminster Fuller, Libby Thayer, and Gregory Blanche; and rejection letters.
  - Correspondence, 1975-1983; 5 (Box 2)
    Contains correspondence relating to Pilgrim at Tinker Creek and other writings. Correspondents include magazines, small presses, literary journals, writers, and friends.
  - Correspondence, 1973-1984, undated; 3 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1983; 6 (Box 4)
  - Writings
    - "Aces and Eights or A Week-end in the Country," handwritten and typescript draft with corrections, undated (Box 5)
    - "Eclipse", undated (Box 5)
    - "The Idea of Prayer in the Theology of Paul Tillich and Henry Nelson Wieman" student paper, 1968 January (Box 5)
    - "Holy the Firm," typescript draft, undated (Box 5)
    - "The Living", undated; 2 (Box 5)
    - Living by Fiction, handwritten and typescript draft with corrections, circa 1981; 1 (Box 5)
    - Living by Fiction, handwritten and typescript drafts with corrections, circa 1981; 5 (Box 6)
    - Pilgrim at Tinker Creek, description of revisions, undated (Box 6)
    - Pilgrim at Tinker Creek, index cards used in the process of writing, undated (Box 10)
    - Teaching a Stone to Talk, handwritten and typescript drafts, undated (Box 6)
    - Teaching a Stone to Talk, handwritten and typescript drafts, undated (Box 7)
    - "Walden Pond and Thoreau," thesis for Hollins College for Masters of Art, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Notes and interviews, undated (Box 7)
    - Notes and unidentified drafts, undated; 3 (Box 7)
    - Assorted handwritten drafts of "critical book", undated; 5 (Box 8)
    - Notes and unidentified drafts, undated; 4 (Box 9)
    - "Old Ideas, Old Stuff", undated (Box 9)
      Notes, writings and writings of others
  - Photographs and negative, 1975 February (Box 9)
    Photographs taken by Gordon Converse of The Christian Science Monitor during trip Dillard made for a story. Photographs are black and white images of Dillard; people and various animals in the jungle of Ecuador; and unidentified male.
    Includes two March 1975 letters to Dillard from Converse and clippings.
  - Diary and notebooks
    - 1962 diary (Box 11)
    - "Irish literature" course notebook, undated (Box 11)
    - Notebook containing notes and drawings, undated (Box 11)
    - Hollins College examination blue books, 1965, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Writings by others, typescript drafts and photocopies, 1977-1979, undated; 3 (Box 11)
    Includes handwritten notes
  - Printed material of writings on and by Dillard, 1972-1975; 5 (Box 12)
    Publicity and reviews on Dillard's works.
  - Printed material of writings on and by Dillard, 1973-1975; 6 (Box 13)
  - Printed material of writings on and by Dillard, 1971-1978; 12 (Box 14)
  - Oversize
    - Printed material of writings on and by Dillard, 1971-1978; 6 folders (Box 15)
- August 1987 Acquisition, undated; 2; 1 box
  Formerly classified as Uncat ZA MS 83.
  - American Childhood, third draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 16)
- February 1989 Acquisition, 1983-1987; 3; Also on one 5.5" and two 3.5" computer disks; 3 boxes
  Formerly classified as Uncat ZA MS 90.
  - An American Childhood, drafts, handwritten and typescript
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disks #1-3 (Uncat ZA MSS 90)
    - Drafts, handwritten and typescript, 1983-1987; 15 (Box 17)
    - Drafts, handwritten and typescript, 1983-1987; 5 (Box 18)
  - The Writing Life, 1987
    Includes other unidentified writings
  - Computer media
    Conditions Governing Access
    Box 19 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Living 2 BIGTOSS benning pie notes newben next rich complete book backup Journal, 1989-ycal-0210-b-0001; 1 (Box 19)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - newnote pate living f + g tosert writing mail outline rahm newfame choosing [illegible] 2 complete book, before June 13 POEM, 1989-ycal-0210-b-0002; 1 (Box 19)
    - Oct 87, TOTAL Book; rahm, pg + line, pate, bigtoes, mail, living, newfame, newben, writing, memoir, choosing, 1989-ycal-0210-b-0003; 1 (Box 19)
- May 2000 Acquisition, 1955-2000; 4; 34 boxes
  Arrangement
  Arranged in nine series: Correspondence, Writings, Notebooks, Teaching Materials, Writings of Others, Drawings, Printed Material on Dillard, Other Papers and Objects, Audiovisual Material.
  Consists of correspondence with various individuals; handwritten, typescript, photocopies and proofs of writings by Dillard; notebooks kept by Dillard in coursework and as part of her creative process; writings by other sent to Dillard for review; drawings made by Dillard; printed material, including magazines, journals and clippings on Dillard; sound recordings and videotapes containing Dillard reading or appearing on radio and television programming; and a small amount of personal effects and papers.
  Formerly classified as Uncat MSS 44.
  - Correspondence, 1955-2000, undated
    Arranged alphabetically by folder titles assigned by Dillard.
    - "Colleagues", 1990-1998; 3 (Box 20)
    - Conley, Cort, 1992-1994 (Box 20)
    - "Experiment letters", 1964 (Box 20)
    - "Family", 1975-1996; 9 (Box 20)
    - "Fan mail", 1982-1989; 2 (Box 20)
    - "Fan mail", 1988-2000; 19 (Box 21)
    - "French letters", 1992 (Box 22)
    - "Friends", 1984-1995; 14 (Box 22)
    - "Friends", 1995-1999; 9 (Box 23)
    - "Letters", 1955-1999; 7 (Box 23)
    - "Letters", 1974-1989; 22 (Box 24)
    - "Letters", 1990-1997; 6 (Box 25)
    - "Letters from students", 1988-1998; 5 (Box 25)
    - "Literary business", 1985-1991; 3 (Box 25)
    - Letter removed from ACC 20000627-cj, 1994 (Box 26)
    - Literary business, including correspondence with editors and Harper Collins contracts, 1991-1998; 4 (Box 26)
    - "Mail from strangers", 1987 (Box 26)
    - "Offers", 1974-2000; 8 (Box 26)
    - "Scholars", 1993-1996 (Box 27)
    - "Strangers", 1995-1996; 4 (Box 27)
  - Writings, 1963-1999, undated
    Arranged into three headings: drafts, printed versions, and student papers.
    - Drafts
      Includes drafts, handwritten, typescript, setting typescripts, and photocopies, some with corrections and notes.
      - "Abstract Expression", undated (Box 28)
      - An American Childhood, 1987, undated; 10 (Box 28)
      - "Annie Dillard Reader", undated; 3 (Box 28)
      - "The Boys", undated (Box 28)
      - "Daddy-Baegling & Jimmy Ryan's Jazz", undated (Box 28)
      - "David Lavery", 1980 (Box 28)
      - "Dispatches", 1998 (Box 28)
      - "Encounters with Chinese Writers [Singing the Blues: Chinese Writers in the United States]", circa 1982; 11 (Box 29)
      - For the Time Being, 1998-1999; 4 (Box 29)
        Includes proofs and research material
      - For the Time Being, 1998-1999; 5 (Box 30)
      - "Holy the Firm", undated; 2 (Box 30)
        Includes proofs, program, clippings
      - "Language for Everyone", undated (Box 30)
      - The Living, undated; 7; Includes one 5.25" computer disk (Box 30)
        Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services: Disk #1 (Uncat MSS44)
        Includes a reading copy
      - The Living, 1991; 15 (Box 31)
        Includes proofs and printed material
      - Living by Fiction, 1974-1998; 4 (Box 31)
        Includes reviews, book jacket and correspondence
      - Mornings Like This:, 1994; 3 (Box 32)
      - "Nonfiction, including speech", undated (Box 32)
      - "Reading", undated (Box 32)
      - "Sophistication", undated (Box 32)
      - "The very large array, dying generations", undated (Box 32)
      - "Why I Live Where I Live", undated (Box 32)
      - The Writing Life book jacket, undated (Box 32)
      - "Yemen", 1983; 2 (Box 33)
      - "Fundamental draft and other drafts including poetry", undated (Box 33)
      - "Unpublished small bits-ideas- quotations-lots about writing, intimacy, sleep, Mamita", undated (Box 33)
      - Unsorted writings, 1978-1997, undated; 4 (Box 33)
    - Printed versions
      Contains printed versions of Dillard's writings.
      - American Heritage, 1987 July-August; 3 (Box 34)
      - American Scholar, 1973 (Box 34)
      - Antaeus, 1980, 1999; 4 (Box 34)
      - The Antigonish Review, 1982, Winter (Box 34)
      - Architectural Digest, 1999 June; 4 (Box 34)
      - The Atlantic, 1973-1994; 8 (Box 34)
      - Bennington Review, 1981 April (Box 34)
      - Black Warrior Review, 1982 Spring (Box 34)
      - Cargoes, 1965-1966; 3 (Box 35)
      - Carolina Quarterly, 1971-1973; 3 (Box 35)
      - Chicago Review, 1975 (Box 35)
      - Christianity Today, 1978 May 5 (Box 35)
      - Christmas Treasury, 1993 (Box 35)
      - Common Knowledge, 1994; 2 (Box 35)
      - Contempora, 1971 May (Box 35)
      - Double Take, 1995 Summer; 2 (Box 35)
      - Ellis, 1982 Fall (Box 35)
      - Erato, 1987 Spring (Box 35)
      - Esquire, 1984-1989; 5 (Box 35)
      - Forefront, 1995 Spring (Box 35)
      - Harpers, 1973-1998; 29 (Box 36)
      - Hartford Courant, 1991 November 24
      - Harvard, 1983 July; 3 (Box 36)
      - Holiday, 1975 September; 2 (Box 36)
      - Hollins, 1985-1992; 2 (Box 36)
      - Image, 1994-1997; 3 (Box 37)
      - Kenyon Review, 1990 Spring (Box 37)
      - Life Magazine, 1988 Fall (Box 37)
      - Living Wilderness, 1973-1975; 5 (Box 37)
      - Mill Mountain Review, 1969 (Box 37)
      - New Orleans Review, 1970 (Box 37)
      - New Republic, 1993 November 1 (Box 37)
      - New York Quarterly, 1972 Winter (Box 37)
      - New York Times Magazine, 1982 May 16
      - New York Times Book Review, 1986-1997 (Box 37)
      - Northeast, 1999 Feb 28 (Box 49)
      - Notre Dame, 1998-1999 Winter; 2 (Box 37)
      - Ontario Review, 1993-1999; 3 (Box 37)
      - Parnassus, 1994 (Box 37)
      - Pittsburgh, 1985-1987; 3 (Box 37)
      - Pittsburgh History, 1994-1995 Winter (Box 37)
      - Ploughshares, 1989 (Box 37)
      - Poetry, 1975 February (Box 37)
      - Quarterly West, 1976 Fall (Box 38)
      - Radcliffe Quarterly, 1983 September; 2 (Box 38)
      - Raritan, undated; 2 (Box 38)
      - Readings and Conversations, 1995 Fall (Box 38)
      - Religion and Literature, 1985 Summer (Box 38)
      - Self, 1982 December (Box 38)
      - Signature, 1983-1986; 4 (Box 38)
      - Southwest Review, 1986 Fall; 2 (Box 38)
      - Sports Illustrated, 1974 February 4 (Box 38)
      - Tikkun, 1988 November; 2 (Box 38)
      - Travel and Leisure, 1974 March (Box 38)
      - Twentieth Century Literature, 1981 Fall (Box 38)
      - Voice, 1989 January 27 (Box 38)
      - Wesleyan, 1985-1989; 4 (Box 38)
      - Wesleyan Writing, 1990 Fall (Box 38)
      - Wilson Quarterly, 1988 January (Box 38)
      - Writer, 1989 November (Box 38)
      - Yale Literary Magazine, 1982 (Box 38)
      - Yale Review, 1985-1988; 2 (Box 38)
    - Student papers
      These writings are from Dillard's coursework.
      - Drafts, handwritten and typescript with notes, 1963-1967, 1973; 8 (Box 39)
        Includes The Hollins Critic 1973 August with short prose by Dillard
  - Notebooks, 1963-1993, undated
    Notebooks contain writings, notes, sketches and drawings. Some are from Dillard's studies. Notebook titles are transcribed from the notebooks.
    - Notebooks, 1965, undated; 4 (Box 40)
    - Notebook, photocopy, 1992-1993 (Box 40)
    - "American literature", undated (Box 40)
    - "Asst. books and shakes", undated (Box 40)
    - "Christian thought", undated (Box 40)
    - "Donne and Milton", undated (Box 40)
    - "Dramatic art", 1966 (Box 40)
    - "England-diary", 1964 (Box 40)
    - "English 152", undated (Box 40)
    - "English", undated (Box 40)
    - "European drama", undated (Box 40)
    - "German literature", undated (Box 40)
    - "History 148", undated (Box 40)
    - "Humanities", undated; 2 (Box 40)
    - "Modern Poetry", 1967 (Box 40)
    - "Modern theology outline", undated (Box 40)
    - "Mysticism", undated (Box 40)
    - "P & R", undated (Box 40)
    - "Poetry and drawings", 1963 (Box 40)
    - "Romantic Poets?", undated (Box 40)
    - "Western P & R", undated (Box 40)
  - Teaching materials, 1980-1988, undated
    - Photocopies of articles, reading lists, printed material and letters of recommendation for students, 1980-1988, undated; 22 (Box 41)
  - Writings of others, 1959-1997, undated
    Includes typescript and printed versions of writings.
    - Chamberlin, Sarah K. "Folded Face to Face", 1996 April (Box 42)
    - Hammer, Michael J." The Thread of Mysticism in Annie Dillard's Pilgrim at Tinker Creek and Holy the Firm", 1984 June (Box 42)
    - Ludwig, Charles H. "A Brief History of Waldron Island", 1959 (Box 42)
    - Madsen, Sarah. "Holding Water", 1989 May (Box 42)
    - McIlroy, Gary. "Ordinary Moons: Walden & Pilgrim at Tinker Creek", 1985 (Box 42)
    - Salzman, Peter A. "Relating with Breslov: an Ethnography of Learning Relationships and Learning Process Among Rebbe Ncahman's Hasidem", 1997 April (Box 42)
    - Schneider, Richard, ed. "Thoreau's Sense of Place", undated (Box 42)
    - Smith, Annick "Homestead", 1995 (Box 42)
    - Strong, Tonya. "Landings", 1996 April (Box 42)
    - Talbot, Thomas. "The Lost Friars of Leeds and other Memories", 1991 April (Box 42)
    - Walker, Gwyneth. "An Expedition to the Pole", 1989 (Box 42)
    - Poems by others, including poems by R. H. W. Dillard, undated (Box 42)
    - Unsorted writings, 1983-1984, undated; 4 (Box 42)
  - Drawings, 1978, undated
    - Drawings, 1978, undated; 6 (Box 43)
    - Sketchbook, undated (Box 42)
  - Printed material on Dillard
    - Clippings, 1983-1984; 6 (Box 44)
    - Clippings and other honors, including Antarctica dispatches, 1999-2000 (Box 44)
    - Magazines and other printed material, 1977-1985; 20 (Box 44)
    - Magazines and other printed material, 1974-1999; 24 (Box 45)
    - Magazines and other printed material, 1974-1990; 32 (Box 46)
    - Scrapbook containing reviews of writings
  - Other papers and objects, 1965-1995, undated
    - American literature bibliographies, 1983 (Box 47)
    - Book lists, 1966, undated (Box 47)
    - Clevidence, William G., discharge papers, 1965 (Box 47)
    - Fork, undated (Box 47)
    - Hair, undated (Box 47)
    - "Old biographical data", 1980 (Box 47)
    - Photographs, 1978-1982, undated; 18 (Box 47)
    - Printing plates
      - Berryman, John, 1970 March (Box 47)
      - Greene, Graham, 1969 July (Box 47)
      - Southern, Terry, 1970 October (Box 47)
      - Van Doren, Mark, 1969 June (Box 47)
    - Spoon, undated (Box 47)
    - UCLA conference, 1982, undated (Box 47)
    - Programs for various events, 1989, 1995 (Box 47)
  - Audiovisual Material, 1987-1996
    Box 48 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copy may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Sound recordings
      All sound recordings are cassettes.
      - An American Childhood, 1991; 7; 7 audiocassettes (Box 48, Item barcode 39002093778729)
      - An American Childhood, (copy), 1991; 7 (Box 48)
        This is a duplicate. The audiocassettes have not been digitized.
      - Annie Dillard Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970344)
      - Annie Dillard Interview (copies), 1989; 1; 3 copies (Box 48)
        These audiocassettes are duplicates. They have not been digitized.
      - Annie Dillard reads "Total Eclipse" from Teaching a Stone to Talk, 1989; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970351)
      - Annie Dillard reads "Total Eclipse" from Teaching a Stone to Talk (copies), 1989; 1; 2 copies (Box 48)
      - Annie Dillard at Four O'Clock, BYU forum discussion, undated; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970377)
      - Annie Dillard Forum, BYU forum discussion, 1989 September 26; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970419)
        Reference copy available.
      - Annie-Chapel Hill (1 of 3 audiocassettes), 1995 January-February; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970427)
      - Annie-Chapel Hill (2 of 3 audiocassettes), 1995 February 10; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970435)
      - Annie-Chapel Hill (3 of 3 audiocassettes), 1995; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970443)
      - Calvin College. Conference 96-Festival of Faith and Writing: Wiersma Memorial Lecture, Annie Dillard: Personal Readings, 1996 April 13; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970518)
      - Calvin College. Conference 96-Festival of Faith and Writing: Wiersma Memorial Lecture, Annie Dillard: Personal Readings, 1996 April 13; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970526)
        This audiocassette appears to be a duplicate.
      - David Evan Thomas. What We Know About Planets, 1999 May 16; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970401)
      - James Boros-"Bivovak", SUNY Stony Brook - Merkin Hall, 1992 April 15-22; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970393)
      - James Harley (for Annie Dillard), 1995; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970385)
      - The Living, Parts 1 & 2, 1992 March 20-24; 2; 2 audiocassettes (Box 48, Item barcode 39002093778703)
      - The Living, Parts 1 & 2 (copies), 1992 March 20-24; 2; 10 copies (Box 48)
      - The Living, Parts 3 & 4, 1992 March 20-24; 2; 2 audiocassettes (Box 48, Item barcode 39002093778711)
      - The Living, Parts 3 & 4 (copies), 1992 March 20-24; 2; 10 copies (Box 48)
        This audiocassette set is a duplicate. They have not been digitized.
      - New Letters on the Air. A Production of New Letters Magazine. Annie Dillard, An American Childhood, 1987 October; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970492)
      - New Letters on the Air. A Production of New Letters Magazine. Annie Dillard, An American Childhood, 1987 October; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970500)
      - PEN/Faulkner. Award for Fiction. Tenth Anniversary Celebration (1 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970476)
      - PEN/Faulkner. Award for Fiction. Tenth Anniversary Celebration (2 of 2 audiocassettes), undated; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970484)
      - Pilgrim at Tinker Creek, 1993; 7; 7 audiocassettes (Box 48, Item barcode 39002093778737)
      - Poetry Center. Annie Dillard, 1989 December 4; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970450)
      - Readings & Conversations, 1995 September-October; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970369)
        Contents for this audiocassette are listed.
        "Autobiography of a Face" by Lucy Grealy
        "Family" by Ian Frazier
        "Flashpoint" by Lynn S. Hightower
        "Touch" by Charlotte Watson Sherman
        "Finding Moon" by Tony Hillerman
      - The Sound of Writing Program, #39: Michael Delp, J. H. Kunstler and Annie Dillard, undated; 1 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002109970468)
    - Video recordings
      - Wiersma Memorial Lecture, Annie Dillard: Personal Reading. FAC 7:30pm; Conference 96-Festival of Faith & Writing; Calvin College, 1996 April 13; YCALMSS422_0001; 1; 01:32:00 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002102300028)
      - Contemporary Literature and the Life of Faith: Listening for God, 1994; YCALMSS422_0002; 1; 01:36:57 (Box 48, Item barcode 39002102300036)
  - Oversize Material
    - Scrapbook containing reviews of writings (Writings), 1974-1979 (Box 49)
    - Printed material containing writings by Dillard (Writings)
    - Magazines (Printed material about Dillard), 1987-1995; 11 (Box 50)